Okay, so let's figure out what these two steps would look like in code.
حسنًا، لنعرف كيف ستظهر هاتان الخطوتان في الكود.
So the first one is you're taking the score for team A and you're changing it.
الأولى هي أخذ النقاط من الفريق A وتغييرها.
And I'm just going to say changing it for now, and
وسأقول تغييرها الآن، و
we'll figure out what we change it to in a second.
سأعرف ماذا حدث بعد التغيير بعد قليل.
You'd have this variable.
سيكون لديك هذا المتغير.
And whenever you want to change the value of this variable,
ومتى أردت تغيير قيمة هذا المتغير،
you need to use the assignment operator.
تحتاج لاستخدام معامل التعيين.
And then you can figure out what you're changing it to.
وعندها يمكنك معرفة ما ستغيرها إليه.
Well, you're increasing it by 3.
حسنًا، ستزيدها بمقدار 3.
Which means that you're taking whatever is currently in Score Team A and
ما يعني أنك ستأخذ أي شيء في نقاط الفريق A حاليًا و
adding 3 to it.
تضيف 3 إليه.
So two things are analogous.
إذن ستجري أمرين متشابهين.
Increasing by 3 and taking the current value and adding 3.
زيادة النقاط بمعدل 3 وأخذ القيمة الحالية وإضافة 3.
So, if we take the current value and
إذن إذا أخذنا القيمة الحالية و
we could get that by just writing the name of the variable.
يمكننا الحصول على ذلك بكتابة اسم المتغير فحسب.
Addition symbol and 3.
رمز الإضافة و3.
We are increasing the current value of Score Team A by 3.
نزيد القيمة الحالية لنقاط الفريق A بمعدل 3.
And of course, end with a semicolon.
وبالتأكيد، ننهي بالفاصلة المنقوطة.
Now I'm not putting an INT here because this variable has already been declared.
الآن، لا أضع INT هنا لأن هذا المتغير تم الأعلان عنه بالفعل.
We did that a few videos ago.
أجرينا ذلك في بضعة مقاطع فيديو سابقة.
It'll be more clear when we look at the code.
سيكون الأمر أوضح عندما ننظر للكود.
Anyways for now let's quickly do this next step.
على كل حال إلى الآن لنجري الخطوة التالية هذه بسرعة.
So to display the score I need to use the display method that I copied over.
إذن لعرض النقاط التي أريدها لاستخدام وظيفة العرض التي نسختها.
So before I was just telling it to display 3.
سابقًا كنت أقول لها أن تعرض العدد 3 فحسب.
But I don't want to display the number 3.
لكنني لا أريد عرض العدد 3.
I want to display whatever value is in Score Team A.
بل أريد عرض قيمة نقاط الفريق A أيًا ما كانت.
So what I actually should put here is Score Team A.
إذن ما يجب وضعه بالفعل هنا هو نقاط الفريق A.
Okay, and I don't want to forget my parenthesis or my semi-colon.
حسنًا، لا أريد أن أنسى الأقواس أو الفاصلة المنقوطة.
All right, let's put this in the code and make sure that everything works.
حسنًا، لنضع هذا في الكود ونتأكد من عمل كل شيء.
So here I am in my java code.
إذن أنا هنا في كود جافا.
And I'm going to go scroll down to this addThree forTeamA method,
وسأمرر لأسفل إلى وظيفة addThree forTeamA
because this is the code that happens whenever I press the plus three button.
لأن هذا هو كود ما يحدث عندما أضغط على زر إضافة 3.
All right, I'm going to remove this for now because this is old code.
حسنًا، سأزيل هذا الآن لأنه كود قديم.
And I'm going to perform my two steps.
وسأجري الخطوتين.
The first one was to take the variable scoreTeamA and
الأولى كانت أخذ المتغير scoreTeamA و
set it equal to its old value plus 3.
ضبطه مساويًا لقيمته القديمة بإضافة 3.
Okay, this is the increase by three step.
حسنًا، هذه هي خطوة الزيادة بمعدل 3.
And then the second step after that is to display it and
ثم الخطوة الثانية بعد ذلك لعرضها و
when I say it, I mean the variable score, Team A.
وعندما أقول ذلك، أعني متغير نقاط الفريق A.
Okay, so there are my two steps.
حسنًا، هاتان كانتا الخطوتين.
Okay, moment of truth, let's hit plus 3 points.
حسنًا، لحظة من الحقيقة، لنضغط على زر إضافة 3 نقاط.
Okay, it increased to 3.
جيد، زادت النتيجة إلى 3.
It's kind of small but it increased to 6, 9, 12, 15, okay, awesome.
إنها نتيجة صغيرة لكنها زادت إلى 6 و 9 و12 و15، حسنًا، مدهش.
This seems to be working.
يبدو أن هذا يعمل.
Now, these other ones don't work, but we didn't expect them to.
الآن، هذان الزران الآخران لا يعملان لكننا لا نتوقع منهم ذلك.